Guide to the Yale Student Diary Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale student diary collection
1838-2002
RU 861
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.31
(7 boxes)
The materials consist of diaries of Yale students.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 41 (YRG 41), Material documenting Yale student life.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are partially restricted. See Collection Contents for information.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of diaries of Yale students.
College students; Diaries; Yale College (1718-1887) -- Students; Yale University -- Students
- Yale student diaries, Circa 1838-1931, 1999; Accession 19ND-A-416
  - Tracy, Howard Crosby (1887), 1866-1934, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Mead, George Harrison (1857S), 1832-1890, 1856-1857 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Moore, William C. (1928) "Forty Days & Forty Nights" A Trip Through Russia, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Sherman, George (1839), 1818-1898. Diary [transcript], 1838-1839 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bruins, J. Frank. (1907) Yale Forest School miscellaneous jottings, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Clarke, Elbert W. (1867, 1865-1866 Junior year transfer student) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Viele, Dorr (1902) Diary, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Welles, Clayton W. (1904) Diary, 1903-1904 (Box 2)
  - Bendix, Peter G. (2000). Diary, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted until 1 Jan 2035.
- Diary and memorabilia of William H. Gage, Circa 1929-1934, 1959; Accession 2004-A-114
  - Diary, Circa 1929-1934, 1959 (Box 1)
- Transcript of diary of Harold T. Clarke (1903), by David S. Clark, 2002; Accession 2005-A-157
  - Transcript of diary of Harold T. Clarke (1903), by David S. Clark, 2002 (Box 1)
- Brinsmade, James Beebee, Jr. (1845), diary, 1843-1853; Accession 2011-A-030
  Scope and Contents
  The two-volume diary primarily documents Brinsmade's junior and senior years at Yale and richly describes campus life. Subjects include prayer meetings, excursions, baseball (the first known reference to baseball at Yale), football, wicket, and an incident of violence toward a local man. William B. Woods, Carter Henry Harrison, and Leonard Bacon are mentioned in the diary. The regular entries end on August 31, 1845, but continue sporadically until February 3, 1853.
  Biographical / Historical
  Brinsmade (1824-1884) entered Yale as a junior in November 1843, and graduated in 1845. He was a member of Scroll and Key and the Linonian Society, for which he served as president. After graduation Brinsmade studied law and became a lawyer.
  - Diary, volumes 1-2, 1843-1853 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
- Frank Johnston Jones (1859) diary, 1857-1858; Accession 2011-A-061
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Gift of Patricia J. McCree, 2011.
  - Frank Johnston Jones (1859) diary, 1857-1858 (Box 1)